I got mugged. I thought it
was the end for me.
Good thing a woman saved me.
Hey.
You're not my type, bro.
Where's my painting?
Ah, the painting?
You took my painting?
Not me.
Look, miss.
I'll prove to you
that I'm not working
with the thieves
who stole your painting.
There's no getting it back anymore.
Yeye wants a balloon!
O, to the M, to the G!
What is this?
Where am I this time?
Ugh! What is this?
I can't be mistaken.
You're the one in the picture
with Ate Ysa from the town hall.
Hey, are you stalking her?
Estong!
- It's just me now. Ysa.
- A different name?
I have...
Dissociative Identity Disorder.
My different personalities
come out because...
of the traumas I went through as a child.
My doctor said,
they're not just imaginary friends.
It's not like I can just switch
personalities whenever I want.
They're a part of me that keeps me alive,
to help me face things that
are hard for me to deal with.
My different personalities
are my mind's way of keeping me safe.
Can I ask
what triggers them to come out?
Trigger?
You're such bad luck!
You have no shame!
You bastard!
It's my fault, right? I'm always
the one to blame?!
It depends.
It can be due to a lot of stress,
fear or anger.
Sometimes even extreme happiness or
excitement can trigger them.
Even something
as simple as a smell,
a person, a place...
or memories—
Come on, let's see.
can be a trigger for me.
How many personalities do you have?
The ones you've met...
are four of my six dominant personalities.
What?
Six?
Kuya.
- Are you stalking your ex again?
- This is different.
This is different, okay?
Do you remember
the woman who saved me?
Mhm.
We saw each other again.
I learned something about her.
What is it? Uh...
Is she loving, sweet, and caring?
Bro, it's complicated.
Complicated? Why?
What's the problem?
Pops, she has a...
mental health condition.
She has different personalities.
I see.
I think I saw this in a movie once.
You know, the one about multiple or
split personalities?
Kuya.
Bro, bro, bro. You're
using the wrong term.
- The correct term is—
- But kuya, I saw that in a movie.
I know. But that's not the right term.
The right term is...
Dissociative Identity Disorder or DID.
"Split" and "multiple"
aren't the right terms.
"D.I.D."?
So that's actually a real thing?
I've never met anyone with a condition
like that before.
Actually, Pops...
I first saw her here in our cafe.
Do you remember the woman
who was painting there?
Let me stay here!
- I want to jump!
- You're so heavy, kuya.
Excuse us, miss.
Oh, that was her?
Huh!
She's one of our regular customers.
She's the one you bothered?
That was the first time I saw her.
Well, duh. You've been
gone for a while, Kuya.
I knew it. I really knew it.
Whenever she orders,
she uses a different names every time.
I know. There's Yeye,
Cacai, Tristan, and Bogart.
Wow.
So you've already met
four of her personalities?
Just wow.
Every personality
has their own mind,
actions, and way of speaking.
Even their likes and
dislikes are different.
So that's why it felt like
I was talking to different people.
That's why...
sometimes I can't remember certain things.
Because when another
personality takes over,
I can't just access those memories.
I hope someone wrote an entry.
Especially when it's someone I don't get
along with.
That's why I want us all to...
get along, so everything's easier and we're
all more aware.
That's it.
Can your condition be...
medically treated?
It's mostly through therapy sessions.
D.I.D. doesn't just simply go away.
It can last a lifetime.
That's why I really want
us all to get along because...
we're not enemies.
We have to learn to work together because,
after all...
we're all just one person.
Looks like you've already set your sights
on someone new.
What about your Australian dream?
I don't think I can handle
another complicated woman, bro.
I just got out of one, remember?
Right.
That's right, my son.
Why don't you just stick with your plan
to study while working in Australia?
That's really the plan, Pops.
I just need to work on the paperwork.
Bogart told me that...
he'll also start writing in this journal.
He wants to make up
for what happened, and...
he also wants to say sorry.
It was never really his
intention to cause a scene.
He just wants to protect all of us.
And all of my other personalities.
I get where you and Bogart are coming from,
but you still need to be careful.
That's right, sweetheart.
Your Nanang is right.
My dear, If you don't
learn to take control,
you could get yourselves into trouble.
Yes, Nong.
I really want to say thank you and...
I also want to apologize.
I'm sorry that I didn't tell
you guys about the painting.
I just don't want to be a burden.
I also don't want to bother anyone.
Oh, please.
Don't think of it that way.
We are one family here,
- okay?
- Right.
Why do you think our street was named...
Magkaisang Bayan Street!
That's why, my dear, you should know
that we're on your side.
Don't hesitate to come to us
if something's wrong, okay?
We'll always be here for you.
Ninang B is right, Ate.
And never think you're a burden, because
we never thought of you that way.
That's right.
My daughter Adel is right, Ysa.
We've always felt
happy every time we help you.
Especially when we know
that you're safe and sound.
We are one family, Ate.
We love one another.
I'm really grateful for all of you.
And also...
you're all right.
Even me,
I want all my personalities
to work together.
That's why I should also learn
how to be open with everyone here.
Ysa, thank you for all the sacrifices you
make for all of you.
And for continuing to paint.
Speaking of...
The painting is still missing.
Hello, Ms. Amara.
I've finished the painting. I'll bring it
to you now.
I'm really sorry, I thought
I'd miss the deadline.
No rush. You can still perfect it.
Just update me. Bye!
I need to give it to Ms.
Amara tomorrow night.
I'm afraid if I don't give it to her
on time, she'll be disappointed.
She's the only one who trusted us.
Oh, sweetheart, don't worry.
We're going to help you find your painting.
- Right?
- Of course!
- That's right, Ysa. Okay?
- Yes, that's right!
Erna and I will post on barangay
pages and community groups online.
I'll also ask about it in the group
chats that I'm a part of.
- I'll talk to our customers about it too.
- Yes, that's right.
I'll also accompany
you to the barangay hall.
Well, go on. Text everyone.
So we can find the painting.
Start messaging in your group chats.
- Bruno's here, he can help.
- Yes, that's right.
There's still no word from our neighbors.
But at least, we already
filed a police blotter.
Then later, we'll get the CCTV footage.
That'll help us find whoever
stole your painting.
Because of that,
let's grab some coffee first.
You never know. The painting might
show up and join us for coffee.
I just hope that painting turns up soon.
Wait a minute.
Yes? Can I help you?
What are you doing here?
This is our café.
I'm on duty right now.
Oh really? I've never seen you here before.
I bet that's just your cover. You've been
following us, haven't you?
She's here?
What about the painting?
Have you found it yet?
Not yet, we're still looking for it.
Wait.
Could you be the one who took the painting?
Maybe you made up those other accomplices
just to throw us off!
Huh?
What if it's here in your café?
- Hey, stop. You're trespassing.
- Hey, wait a minute.
Hey, schoolmate, you're not allowed here.
You guys know each other?
You know me?
Bro, she's my school mate.
Are you looking for me?
Keep dreaming.
Let me through!
I just want to see!
- It's not here, okay?
- Let me look!
Stop, or we'll take this to the barangay.
You're not allowed here.
Hi Ysabelle, Just a reminder
for the painting delivery tonight.
Looking forward to seeing it.
- Just let me through, okay? I just need to look.
- School mate, you're really not allowed here.
What you're doing is trespassing.
You're not allowed there!
Just one look!
My dear.
I heard you. I know what you're thinking.
Lola Iska.
My dear, I know what you're thinking.
Ysa?
Lola Iska!
If you're suspicious of this guy, Adel,
then bring him along as
we look for the painting.
No, Lola.
Let's look for it ourselves.
Lola?
Dear...
The more eyes we have,
the sooner we'll find what's missing.
That's true.
But we're still on duty right now, Ysa.
It's Lola Iska.
Lola?
Lola...
Lola Iska?
Dear.
Uh—
Come, give me a hand.
Help me look for the painting.
- Bro, you've got this, okay?
- Alright.
Lola. Alright, now, listen to me. I'll tell
you everything that happened, okay?
The mugger and I were walking here.
We were walking happily.
Then he suddenly said "this is a holdup."
So I got scared.
I told him "Why are you robbing me,
I thought we were friends?"
Then, he took my wallet.
Then I tried to snatch it back, so we were
scrambling like this.
And then, he suddenly
kicked me like this—bam!
Bam! I fell right here. But he didn't...
He didn't stop there.
Then, he continued to beat me up.
Pak! Pak! Pak! Pak! Pak!
Then I was like, Pak! Pak! Pak! Pak!
Can you stop?
You're really gonna get it.
Tell her, not me.
My verdict is...
He's telling the truth, my dear.
See?
Because everything he said is consistent
with what Bogart wrote in the journal.
He finally wrote an entry on the journal.
That doesn't help us a lot, Lola Iska.
How can we really prove
that this guy is innocent?
That's what I've been saying. That's why...
we need to have the CCTV footage.
We have to see it.
Okay?
Come on.
Don't follow or get close
to Ate Ysa anymore.
She might get worse again!
If Bogart comes out, I won't be able to
stop or calm him down.
Love?
It's only a one-kilo order.
Why are you preparing
enough for a feeding program?
Sorry, my bad.
Just let me do it.
That's it.
You ordered just one kilo, right?
Here's the payment.
Thank you.
Alright.
I'm just worried about Ysa.
You know it feels like...
they're all reverting
to how they used to be.
She gets triggered so easily again.
You know, it's really that man's fault.
I told you.
We're not supposed to mention
that man's name.
Especially here in our house.
It's a house rule.
His name is Lorenz.
You can't blame Ysabelle.
We taught her how to love.
And how to be kind.
That's the problem.
Ysabelle has always been so obedient.
She obeyed us.
She loved us.
But she also got scared.
She ended up distancing herself.
That's just it.
But then, Lorenz...
gave up right away.
We never heard from him again.
You know, love...
I still hope that
one day, Ysa will meet
a man who'll love her completely.
Someone who will not give up on her.
As for me...
I don't want to trust anyone anymore.
I don't want to see our
daughter get hurt again.
Especially after she almost hurt herself.
Oh, hey, Barbs!
I'll get my order of Denurado rice—
Girl!
- Oh right.
- The Denurado rice.
Yes. Denurado rice.
One kilo, right?
Thank you.
Come back next time, okay?
Alright, take care!
You okay?
No.
Who is she this time, bro?
Lola Iska.
The fifth personality I've met.
Lola?
What? Like older than me?
Something like that, Pops.
Only in the way she thinks and acts.
Estong, didn't you say
her painting was missing?
Why don't you help her find the painting?
I feel sorry for her.
And remember, she also saved you.
Pops...
I already offered my help.
She doesn't want it.
Then that girl who was
with her also said
I might trigger her even more.
Nah, bro.
Popsy is right. Just help her out.
Also, wasn't Ysa the one
who didn't want help?
She's different now. She's a grandma.
What about that girl?
Bro...
I'll take care of it.
The girl?
That's easy.
Watch.
Hey, gorgeous!
Just order whatever you want. It's on me.
I can pay for it.
Besides, who do you think you are?
We're not even friends.
I mean, we can be friends.
Pass. I have enough friends already.
And your flattery won't work on me.
You're not my type.
Oh, my.
Excuse me.
Oops!
Oh, no!
- What the heck?!
- I'm so sorry!
I didn't mean to.
You're so annoying!
I'm so sorry.
Gosh! Where's the
restroom? You're so annoying.
The restroom?
- You're so annoying!
- The restroom?
Right over there.
Three hundred meters, turn...
turn around.
You're frustrating!
- So annoying!
- Just go straight.
Yes, right there.
Sorry.
What have I told you?
That's your chance, bro.
Thank you, bro.
Lola Iska!
Wow! You really got his face right, Lola!
He really looked like this!
I just based it on what Bogart
wrote in his journal.
The best thing to do
is find this person first.
While we...
still don't have the CCTV footage.
You're right, Lola.
Let's find him first.
Ouch.
Lola?
You want me to...
carry you?
Oh, no need!
I can manage.
I might end up aching even more.
I think you're the one
who's getting tired, dear.
Do you want to take a rest for a while?
Just a little bit.
Is it okay with you?
Let's rest for a while?
But you're still so young.
But...
Alright.
But just for a short while, okay?
We might run out of time.
Okay, Lola.
Then, we'll start looking again.
Wow, it's so accurate.
You even got his beard right.
This is impressive.
Even his eyes.
Yay! Play! Play! Play!
Lola?
I'll join! Let me join!
Why do you talk like that?
You're a grown-up!
Do you even know what we're playing?
Pass! You don't have a clue!
Let's get out of here!
I want to play! Yeye wants to play!
Kuya, your girlfriend is crazy!
Come on, let's go!
Want to play with me instead?
Come, let's play!
I'll play with you instead.
Let's play?
Kuya Estong?
You remember me?
Thank you!
Balloon!
Yes!
Let's play, just the two of us!
Let's play?
Of course!
Let's play!
I'll go first, okay?
- That's cheating!
- Nope, nope, nope!
You're a cheater!
So close!
You lost!
Your turn.
I'll lose it you'll get through that, okay?
Come on, then.
Wow, you're quick!
- Wow, you're so good!
- I won!
Alright, here.
Congrats, Yeye!
You're so good, Yeye. You got me there!
Kuya Estong?
Yes? What is it, Yeye?
Are we best friends now?
Sure! We're best friends now!
Pinky swear?
Pinky swear!
We're now best friends, okay?
So now that we're best friends...
Maybe you could help
me find Ate Ysa's painting.
- Okay?
- Yes!
Let's go?
Go faster, best friend!
Yeye, you're so fast!
We're so sorry.
Sorry.
Are you okay, Yeye?
Yeye?
O to the M to the G!
To the H to the I!
Oh my god.
The designs are so pretty!
This one!
Oh, I like this!
Oh my God!
This is so nice!
Oh my God, wait a minute.
I think this one is perfect for you.
The color, the shape,
the flowery design. And...
It matches with your hair color. Perfect!
I know. Yeah!
Right?
Wait.
Yes?
No offense, but...
Mhmm.
Are you gay?
No!
But you know, I've always been
a fan of fashion! Right?
Fashion!
I know you. You're the one
I saw at Ukay Orayt.
Right?
You're right!
Alright, I know!
Why are you always with me?
Are you my admirer?
Do you have a crush on me?
How did you know I'm your admirer?
Yes, that's right! Because you know
your fashion sense is really top-notch!
Top-notch!
Then you should sign up to my fan club!
And then I'll welcome you!
You'll welcome me?
Yeah!
Oh and then welcome to me— to Cacainatics?
Well, that'll do.
I love it!
Look, this one's perfect!
It's a hundred and two pesos, mister.
- One hundred and twenty pesos?
- Yes, mister
Can I put it in my bag already?
- It's so expensive.
- Okay.
I'll get this and I'll get four of these.
Same price for this?
- And then...
- Yes, mister.
Oh, their colors are
nice! Which one is better?
- Are you the one paying for these?
- Yes, ma'am. That looks nice.
Oh, I choose this one!
Hey, those cost one
hundred twenty pesos each.
- Ate Ysa, where are you now.
- Hello, hello, Kuya?
Hello? Hello?
Hello? Kuya!
Kuya? Kuya?
Oh, kuya, I'm glad you picked up.
Where are you?
I'm here right behind you.
What do you mean "behind you"?
Kuya, you're not behind me—
It's just me.
How could he answer you when he left
his phone here?
Oh, come on.
Seriously?
I was calling him this whole time.
This is your fault!
You think I didn't know you
intentionally threw the water at me?!
Hold on, how can you say that?
Your style sucks!
It's awful!
Um...
Miss?
Sorry about my youngest.
He meant no harm.
Yeah, that's right.
My brother just wants to help your Ate Ysa.
You're just really annoying!
What if your brother
will trigger her again?!
It's always your brother!
Don't worry.
Estong wouldn't just abandon Ysa.
Actually, last night we saw him researching
how to interact
with people like Ysa.
Right!
So don't underestimate my brother, okay?
He may look like a fool
compared to me, but...
he's got his own strengths too.
Especially if she likes the girl.
What?
Does he have a crush on Ate Ysa?
No! That can't happen!
What do you mean, that can't happen?
What do you want? That my brother
has a crush on you instead?
You don't understand! It's a long story,
but it can't happen!
Ate Belle might come out!
Ate Belle?
Wait, so...
That's her sixth personality?
That's how scary she is?
Yes!
If Ate Belle really comes out,
she'll definitely put
your brother in danger!
He'll have nowhere to run!
Jayden.
You should just accompany Adel.
You have a motorcycle, right?
That way, you'll find them both faster.
Okay, Popsy. You're right.
Come on, let's get going!
Hey!
Don't be so fussy. They
could be fighting already!
They might've already hurt each other.
Come on.
Okay, that's perfect.
And then—
What if I'll place this hand, so I can—
Yeah!
That's right. Okay and then...
Try tilting your face a
bit to the right. Okay?
Like this?
Yes! Oh my God, that's the angle!
Woo!
Mhmm!
One more.
Jestoni!
What's going on?
Okay, that's it.
It's done!
Oh, I wanna see!
Let me see! Let me see!
Look!
- Right?
- It's so nice!
I know!
I look like a star there!
- Yeah!
- I look like an artist!
I know, right? Clock it!
It's so nice!
Oh! My legs are so long!
Yeah...
Can we just stick with...
just Estong?
I'm not used to being called Jestoni.
No.
No, no, no.
You know why?
Because Estong...
Why?
Kinda sounds lame.
And I don't like—
I like all things pretty, you know?
That's why I'll call you Jestoni.
There's Estong, but Jestoni! Right?
Right!
Yeah, it came from Jestoni.
Yeah! Jestoni!
So, you're good?
So can we now head to the barangay hall
to get the CCTV footage for the painting?
Remember?
O to the M to the G!
Why didn't you remind
me? I completely forgot!
We have to look for that painting.
We have to get it.
Yes!
Because the whole world
has to see my beautiful artwork!
Yes! I know!
We have to get it. We
have to look for it, okay?
I did everything I could for her!
I even did her laundry,
yet she still left me!
So...
Let's go! Let's go now!
Cacai?
Have I been with you
this whole time, Estong?
Tristan?
Uh— yes. We need to go somewhere.
I don't want to go.
I'm too sad at the moment.
Oh.
Alright.
Let's just take a walk.
Let's walk while being sad.
I don't to walk either.
What do you wanna do?
Whoa! One hundred!
So good! Your turn.
I don't want to.
You go ahead, bro.
Tristan. If...
you're not going to sing with me,
maybe you could come with me to help
look for Ysa's painting.
What do you think?
I don't want to.
They're the only ones who want to find it.
They're the only ones who wanted to be
recognized because of that painting.
How about you?
What do you want?
I just want to be happy.
How about you?
I want to...
Your question's too difficult to answer.
The truth is...
I don't know.
I don't know if I'll ever find out.
You said it yourself,
"Think positive."
What was it your father used to say again?
While there's still breath in us...
there's still a fight in us.
Are you okay?
Hey are you okay?
Tristan?
Are you okay?
What happened?
Ugh... my neck's starting to hurt.
Oh no!
Hey! Oh God!
She lost—
Lola Iska?
Lola— Lola is passing out!
Here, here.
It's okay.
Lola?
Ugh, my neck's killing me.
What did those kids eat?
Pork rinds and beer.
What does it say?
She definitely drunk.
I guess she really drunk.
What about you?
Aren't you drunk yet?
I'm not yet.
What's with those kids?!
They're going to give me a heart attack!
- Lola, calm down.
- Oh gosh, it hurts!
Relax, relax.
What were those kids thinking?!
Easy, easy. You might give yourself a
heart attack.
Go ahead and carry it.
Is she dead?
She just fell asleep, okay?
She's drunk.
I need my medicine!
Medicine, we need medicine!
Lola?
Am I getting too heavy for you, dear?
You can put me down now.
Not at all, Lola.
Better than you having a heart attack.
I got this.
Uh, lola?
Was it Tristan eating chicharon
that triggered you?
Is that why your neck started hurting?
Yeah.
That's why I keep telling those kids...
That they should always...
think about the others as well.
Because whatever they do...
whatever they think, or feel...
it affects everyone else too.
That's what they need
to get through their heads.
I didn't realize Ysa was carrying so much.
What was that, dear? Heavy?
- Well, you can put me down now.
- Oh, no, no. That's not what I meant.
You can stay there as long as you want.
No.
It's okay, you can put me down now.
I can manage.
And...
I have this.
Oh, I almost forgot.
You haven't properly greet your lola yet.
Come on.
Lola?
We're in the middle of the street, Lola!
There we go.
Where am I?
We're just in the street.
Let's get going, my dear.
Dear.
Do we still got a long way to go?
I'm getting a little tired.
Just a little more, Lola.
You never know.
Maybe the universe will
help us out, and we'll just run
into the mugger. Right?
That'd be awesome.
Dear...
Yes, Lola?
Isn't that the mugger?
It is!
Hey! You!
Come here!
You!
Hey!
Get over here!
What? You want to run away?!
You think you can escape now?!
Forgive me, please!
Why did you even bother
making us chase you?
Why? Did anyone tell you to chase me?
You didn't have to, right?
So you're a smartass, huh?
The nerve of you!
Bogart, don't.
You don't need to hurt him.
You might hurt yourself and the others.
He's right, ma'am!
You should listen to him!
Tell me the truth.
You're accomplices with the guys
who stole my painting, huh?
No! I don't have any accomplices.
What painting?
Are you sure about that?
I was just passing by.
I was just doing it for my sick child.
Just make sure you're telling the truth!
You won't answer to the
law. You'll answer to my fists.
Do you understand?!
Yes, boss!
Boss, if you want,
you can accompany me to the hospital.
Get out of here.
You're really pissing me off.
Hey, calm down.
Don't worry.
We'll find Ysa's painting eventually.
It's okay, Bogart.
Calm down.
Estong.
Ysa.
Welcome back.
- Ate Ysa.
- Oh, there they are.
Adel?
Bro!
Ate Ysa!
Are you okay? Did he hurt you?
No.
I was completely safe because of Estong.
See?
Did you hear that?
I told you.
Estong is really caring.
Yes.
He cares with all his heart.
What are you saying, bro?
Are you sure, Ate Ysa? Maybe you just
didn't remember.
No.
I saw everything.
I remember everything because they showed
me everything.
They showed you everything?
How?
The barangay hall texted me.
They said we can check
the CCTV footage now.
That's way too blurry.
It caught the men who
stole Ate Ysa's painting.
But the footage is glitching
that's why it's blurry.
We can't see their faces.
Ysa.
Why is that painting so important to you?
It's important to me because...
It's my dream.
It's our dream.
Oh.
Didn't I tell you? We're not all the same.
But that was the only way I could think of
to bring us together.
That's also what our doctor told us.
That even though we
have different personalities...
it's good for us to have
shared dreams,
shared goals.
Like that.
I see.
Estong?
I'm sorry.
I know today wasn't easy.
You've been through
so much with a lot of us.
You had to take care a lot of us.
Sorry for bothering you.
Um. Ysa...
The truth is...
I enjoyed it.
Different personalities.
Different vibes.
It was fun.
- When will I get the painting?
- Oh no.
Ms. Amara texted me.
What am I going to do?
She's asking about the painting.
What if...
You just tell her the truth, and then...
create a new artwork.
It's not that easy.
Ate Ysa promised.
She was commissioned to paint that for
Ms. Amara's house.
He's right, you know?
It's better to tell the truth.
And of course,
don't lose hope because...
While there's still breath in us...
There's still fight in us.
Let's go, Ate.
Alright, that's enough.
Let's have something to eat.
- Come on?
- You're not coming!
Ate Ysa, are you okay?
- Ysa?
- I found the painting.
You can't take this away.
I won't return it.
That's mine!
Sir, that belongs to me.
I made that myself.
I completely understand
if you won't give me
another chance
or a spot for the next exhibit.
Ysa?
Hey! Ysa!
- Ysa! Ysa!
- Ate? Ate!
Sometimes, the body
decides it needs to rest.
Like a reset, Doc?
Something like that.
The mind protects itself
the best way it knows how.
There!
Wait. One more.
Ow.
What are your intentions
toward Ysa?
Ysa and I only became
friends yesterday.
Are we friends now?
Uh—why not?
Oh!
- I didn't mean to—
- You're paying for this!
How am I supposed
to sell this now?
Pay up!